我很清醒
I am awake.
你跟课堂上那会儿完全不一样了
You are not how I remember you from class.
我说  真的  完全不像你了
I mean, like, not at all.
老兄  这些连七千都不到
Dude, this isn't even 7 grand.
我那兄弟要八千五呢
My guy wants 85.
这是我所有的钱了
This is all the money I have in the world.
你不是毒贩嘛  讨价还价呀
You are a drug dealer. Negotiate.
把房车买回来
Buy the RV.
我们明天开工
We start tomorrow.
来吧  来吧  宝贝儿
Work it, work it, baby.
唷  哥们  你太变态了
Yo, this is sick, brother.
那是自然
Totally.
老天  杰西老弟
God. Yo, Jesse.
我这里有两个美女也想加入哦
I got these two fine ladies want to participate.
你银子够吗
You got the funds?
老子有的是银子
Oh, I got the funds.
美女们来看看老子底子够不够厚呀
Hey, would you ladies like to meet my fat stack?
快过来  来吧
Get in here. Come on.
唷  你
Hey, yo, yo.
唷  有香槟没有
Yo, you got champagne?
不要便宜货
None of that cheap stuff.
老子要死贵的那种
I want the expensive shit.
唐培里侬的
Don Perig-non.
400块一瓶
It's 400 a bottle.
既然如此
Oh, well, in that case,
那就只要两瓶好了
I'll only have two.
还有  要那种细细的高脚杯
Oh, and I want the tall, skinny glasses.
老子喜欢细高脚杯
I like those skinny glasses.
詹姆斯·邦德喝啥咱喝啥
That's what James Bond drinks.
杂种们  老子就这么牛
Mofos, I'm all about that.
我说  杰西老弟  我很好奇
Yo, Jesse, man, I gotta ask.
你的票子从哪儿来的
Where'd you get all the cheddar?
肯定是走了狗屎运了
Must be moving mad volume.
说来搞笑
It's totally funny.
你知道最搞笑的是什么
You want to know what's funny?
是什么
What's funny?
有个老家伙  他白送我的
This old dude, he gave it to me.
-什么  -他白送我的
- What? - He gave it tme.
这些钱是他一辈子的积蓄
It's, like, his entire life savings.
什么  为什么呀
What? Why?
因为他是个老傻帽  就因为这个
Because he's a dumb-ass. That's why.
老天
Oh, God.
来吧  浪子们  长命百岁
Yes! Whoo! All right, living large, players.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不  该我谢你
No, thank you.
这可真是...
That was...
爽歪了  伙计
...awesome, bro.
回见
Later.
老哥
Oh, man.
我死定了
Oh, I'm so dead.
我只剩下...该死的
I only got... oh, damn.
只剩下  一千四了
I only got, like, 1,400.
华夫屋夜总会也不错
Waffle House, yeah.
不是  老哥
No, man.
那哥们给我钱  是让我买房车的
I'm supposed to use that dude's money to buy an RV.
你要房车干什么
What you want with an RV for?
就是...
'Cause it's like...
就是...你别管了
It's like... never mind.
老天哪
Jesus.
我没辙了  只能  出城跑路
Now I've got to, like, leave town
隐姓埋名什么的了
or change my identity or something.
那家伙敲诈我
Guy's blackmailing me.
他那人...就是一凶犯
He's got, like, a criminal mind, yo.
房车是不
RV, huh?
老弟  我能帮你搞定
I can hook you up, bro.
哥给你搞辆房车
I can totally get you an RV.
不成  我今天就要  现在就要
No, I need it today... now.
没问题  咱走
No problem. Let's go.
你真能帮我搞辆房车
You're telling me you can get me an RV?
大早上6点钟  只花一千四百块么
For 1,400 at 6 in the morning?
好极了
Right on.
用不用签个字什么的
So do I need to sign something or something?
不用  这叫无协议交易
Nah, it's, like, a no-paperwork-type deal.
很荣幸跟你做生意
Pleasure doing business with you.
走吧  该闪了
Come on, we gotta bounce.
-什么  -真的  唷  开车走呀
- What? - For real, yo. Get it out of here.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：Silmar     zlean     金翠     小路
时间轴：Angelica     特效：Will
■
后期：冰河       校对&监制：蛐蛐
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第五集
我的上帝
Oh, my God,
我爱死这地板了
I love this floor.
脚感棒得不行
This feels fantastic.
温度是可控的吗
Can you control the temperature?
是啊  你手边应该有个开关
Uh, yeah, there should be a switch right next to you there.
就是调温度的
It's a thermostat.
泰德
Ted...
这一定是
This has got to be
历史上最伟大的发明
the most amazing invention ever.
我知道  装修包工头劝我装的
I know. Contractor talked me into it.
看起来有点奢侈
Seemed kind of extravagant,
可是这东西真是
but I gotta tell you,
用了一次  你就忘不掉了
once you try it, you can't go back.
我就永远没这种命
I can never find anything in this Buick.
愿意的话  你可以把东西放在这里
You know, you could leave a few things here if you want.
去叫你爸来吃饭吧
Why don't you go get your dad?
好
Sure.
老爸
Hey, Dad.
Dad.
什么事
Uh, yeah.
妈妈问你
Um, Mom's asking,
要来吃晚饭吗
want to come to dinner?
好  我马上就来
Uh, yeah, I'll be right there.
你没在听我讲话  我不知道
You're not listening to me. I don't know.
是啊  你倒装得像
Yeah, right, like you don't know.
我怎么跟你说的
Wha... What did I just say?
电话给我  给我
Give me the phone. Give it.
你没背着我跟人做交易吗
Like you didn't make some deal behind my back.
对的  我没有
Correct. I did not.
我当时正在等红灯
I was sitting at a stoplight,
想我自己的事  那个...
minding my own business, when the man th...
那个人
uh, the man...
那个孩子就往我车窗里扔了一包钱
the kid threw a bag of money through my window.
我才不管  那钱是我的  你欠我
Whatever, man. You owe me that money.
-让我跟他讲  -我不欠你
- Let me talk to him. - I owe you...
我什么都不欠你的
I owe you nothing,
这件事情我会查清楚  你要信任我
and I will get to the bottom of this. Trust me.
信任你
Trust you?
信任你  这可真是好主意
Trust you? That's a good one.
好呀  好呀  我就信任你
Yeah, yeah, that's what I'm going to do.
杰西  你还想跟我谈信任么
You want to talk about trust, Jesse?
那咱们谈谈信任
Let's talk about trust.
我告诉你不要用我的配方
I told you not to cook my formula,
可你自顾自的就用了
and you went ahead and did it anyway.
我又没跟你保证我不用
Cause I never said I wouldn't cook it
配方又不是你的  是我们共有  懂吗  贱人
Cause it ain't yours. It's ours. Plural, bitch.
你未经我的允许
You did not have my permission.
我只知道  我只得了该得的一半
Alls I know is I got half the money I'm due,
剩下的都进了你腰包
and you got the rest.
太过了  你这是狮子大开口
Escalating... You're escalating.
我就开了怎么着  你给我听着
Escalate this. You know what?
毒是我制的  钱是我赚的
My meth, my money!
是我一个人里里外外
I will be a one-man glass factory.
全天24小时闷在房车里...
I will rock that RV 24...
封得太严
It's buttoned up tight.
毛都瞧不见
Can't see a damn thing.
我觉得不像
I ain't feeling it.
没烟  没味道  没废弃物
No smoke, no smell, no waste.
不可能是制毒的
There's no cook.
可能是他们做的局
Could be they're setting up.
我听见里面有动静
I heard movement inside.
我看今晚就这样吧
I say we call it a night,
有了搜查证再来
come back with a search warrant.
不能让这浑球溜出我的视线
I'm not letting this sucker out of my sight.
一定有办法的
There's got to be a way.
一定有办法  一定有办法
There's got to be a way. There's got to be a way.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
你他妈的在那里干什么
What the hell you doing up there?
-你这个变态  -操
- You some kind of a pervert? - Shit.
回到车上去  一切都很顺利
Go back to your trailers. Everything's okay.
那人是退伍军人  他很酷
Guy's VFW. He's cool.
好吧  听好了
All right, I'll tell you what.
我们得再进一步调查那对情侣
We're gonna check out a couple more.
差不多就一上午的时间  你觉得怎么样
Then we're gonna call it a morning. Okay? What do you say?
不行  我要回家
Can't. Gotta get home.
怎么  得了气管炎还是怎么了
Why, you leave your balls in your wife's purse or what?
我要回去整理东西
Gotta pack.
你要去哪里
Where you headed?
德克萨斯州
Texas.
是谁啊
Hey, there.
汉克
Hank?
汉克是你吗
我可以进来吗
Can I come in?
宝贝
Hey, babe.
嗨
Hey.
昨晚怎么样
How did it go last night?
不错
Good.
抓到犯人了吗
Catch the bad guys?
没有
Uh, nope.
要我给你做早餐吗
Want me to make you some breakfast?
不用了  我...
Nah. I'm--
我洗完澡就得回去
I'm heading back out after this.
马上么
Now?
你整晚都在工作
You worked all night.
你得睡一会  汉克
Get some sleep, Hank.
那些休闲车跑不了多远的
Those RVs aren't going anywhere.
那是旅行房车  玛丽
They're recreational vehicles, Marie.
它们就是用来旅游的
That's what they do.
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
我和布朗卡谈过了
I spoke with Blanca.
她说史蒂芬会去埃尔帕索那里  是这样么
She said that Steven's going to El Paso?
没错
Yeah.
我想知道对此你有什么看法
I was just wondering how you feel about that.
我拒绝了
I turned it down.
事情结束了
End of story.
好的  好的
Good, good.
我终于可以松一口气了
Jesus, God knows I'm relieved.
是的  我得留在这里
Yeah, well, I needed some time here
进行深入调查
because I'm deep into this investigation
但不能两头兼顾
and couldn't do both,
所以我擅自做了决定
so I made a judgment call.
你知道你可以向我倾诉  对吧
You know that you can talk to me about things, right?
你不必独自承担这一切
You don't have to go through this alone.
你都要把人逼死了
Do you ask me which lead bib to put on someone
还管这点屁事么
before you nuke them?
上帝  玛丽
Jesus, Marie.
我决定好了
I made a decision.
我不想讨论这些事了
I'm not going through anything.
我只想做好我的工作
I'm doing my job.
我想...
I would like--
我知道  你想在乔治敦有套公寓嘛
I know, I know, a condo in Georgetown. I know.
如果你让我说完
If you would let me finish,
我原本打算说我愿意听你发牢骚
I was going to say I'd like to be included.
仅此而已
That's all.
你不用为我的事业担心
Don't you worry about my career.
没出啥问题
My career is just fine.
你不想去吗
Did you not want to go?
我没有责备的意思  我只是...
I don't blame you. I just--
你上班或者去哪儿要晚了吧
Aren't you late for work or something?
我是说  上次发生的事情
I mean, what happened last time,
那样的经历
it would make perfect sense
会让你再也不想回到那里
for you to not want to go back.
眼下我于此有要务在身
I'm on to some important stuff right here, right now,
跟墨西哥州没有丝毫关系
and Mexico doesn't have a damn thing to do with it.
总是有人怀疑
Anyone who doubts that--
我一直都表现出色
I'm doing some actual good out here,
但我得到的只有无耻诽谤
and all I get are these bullshit accusations!
为什么每个人都觉得我在游手好闲
What, everyone thinks I'm jerking off on this thing? Fine.
我勤勤恳恳的工作  我知道我做的很好
But I'm onto something. I know it.
你能理解我么
You understand me?
你在听我说话吗
You hear me?
这是什么意思
What exactly is this?
我来告诉你我认为这是什么
I'll tell you what I think it is.
小花招  让我再次制毒的小花招
A ploy. A ploy to get me cooking again...
很明显就是这样
And an obvious one at that.
你什么意思
How do you mean?
就像我很确定你会雇佣瘾君子
As if I would seriously believe you would hire an addict.
杰西·平克曼吗
Jesse Pinkman?
你可以选择解释与否
Recovering or not--
之前你为他做担保
You vouched for him previously.
我相信了你的承诺
I took you at your word.
不  不  让我澄清一下
No, no, no, no, let me be clear.
一五一十的解释给你听
Let me be perfectly clear.
在我的监督下  杰西可以胜任工作
Jesse was capable of working under my supervision.
而凭此相信他可以单独制度
Trusting him with a solo venture,
则是另一回事
that's quite another matter.
没有我  他只能制造出
How he could possibly produce
二流的产品
anything other than a mediocre product at best.
据我所知  他的产品的确有点
I am told his product was more or less consistent
未达到我预期的质量
with the quality I had come to expect.
有点儿
More or less?
有点儿  你是说真的吗
More or less? Really?
真没想到
Wow.
伙计  那真是...
Boy, that is the--
我们能否抛开成见
Talk about setting the bar low.
除非你不想这样
Except you don't do that--
不计前嫌
set the bar low.
那么  我应该得出什么结论
Therefore, what conclusion am I left to draw? Hm?
你坚信
That you believe
在我的配方专利问题上
I have some proprietary kind of selfishness
我很自私
about my own formula.
是这样吗
Hm?
我猜你是觉得
Some sort of overweening pride, I suppose,
我的高傲自大
that you think
拖累了我
simply overwhelms me,
蒙蔽了我的双眼
clouds my judgment.
但事实并非如此
But it doesn't.
当然不是
Absolutely not.
我只不过是在向化学致敬
I simply respect the chemistry.
这门科学必须受到尊重
The chemistry must be respected.
我为我之前的态度向你道歉
I apologize for being so transparent.
你愿意跟我跑一趟吗
Would you take a drive with me?
我想给你看些东西
I'd like to show you something.
一切顺利吗
Hi. Is everything okay?
她刚喝完一整瓶
She's already finished an entire bottle,
但看起来还很饿  后来她睡着了
but she still seemed hungry. Than she fell asleep.
我想等她醒来后再给她喝一瓶
I was thinking I'd give her another when she wakes up.
好的好的  当然可以
Yeah-- yeah, yeah, absolutely.
没问题  把宝宝养的白白胖胖的
Absolutely. Fatten that baby up.
我会的
Will do.
恩  就这些吗
Um...was that it?
你在哪里  在工作吗
So where are you. Are you at work?
是的  我正在工作
Yeah. Yeah, I'm at work.
我不能讲太久
I-- I shouldn't be much longer.
有什么事吗
Is that okay?
你知道我很爱这个小小粉嫩宝贝
You know I love my little Pookums.
我想  今后的18年
You can leave her with me for the next 18 years
都可以由我来照顾她
as far as I'm concerned.
太好了
Great.
谢谢你  玛丽
Thanks, Marie.
你...确定没有问题了吗
Are you-- Are you sure you're okay?
亲爱的  怎么了
Sweetie, what is it?
告诉我吧
Come on.
是汉克
It's Hank.
他怎么了
What about him?
我不知道  该如何与他交流
I don't know how to talk to him.
我不知道还能和他说什么
I don't know what to say to him anymore.
我不知道...
I don't know how to--
自从埃尔帕索...
Ever since El Paso--
可能更早...
Ever since maybe before...
是的
Yeah.
天知道他在那里到底遭受了什么
God knows he went through a lot down there.
同事就在他眼前被炸死
People blown up right in front of him,
血溅得到处都是
blood everywhere,
上个星期
and last week
埃尔帕索说想要他归队
El Paso said they want him back.
然后呢
Yeah?
他没有答应  史蒂芬·戈麦斯会顶替他
He's not going. Steve Gomez is going in his place, and...
我也不清楚自己的想法
I don't know how I feel about that.
留在这里他肯定更安全  不是么
Well, he's certainly a lot safer up here, isn't he?
当然  但我希望他一切平安
Of course, and I want him safe.
我不知道他想要什么
I can't tell what he wants.
他从来不向我提起
He won't talk to me.
他几乎不回家
He hardly even comes home.
没日没夜的工作
He works all day, all night.
几乎不吃东西  也不怎么和我说话
Barely eats, barely speaks to me.
就好像有什么东西把他掏空了一样
It's like something's eating him away from inside.
他变了
He's just not the same.
变了很多
He's not.
直面死亡  人会改变很多
Facing death, it changes a person.
肯定是这样  你觉得呢
It has to, don't you think?
我猜你也注意到沃尔特的变化了
I guess you've notice a change in Walt.
请进
Please.
这是什么地方
What is this?
你的新实验室
Your new lab.
天啊
My God.
钍氧化物
Thorium oxide...
用作催化剂床层
for a catalyst bed.
看看这反应器尺寸
Look at the size of this reaction vessel.
怎么会有1200升这么大的容积
Why, that's got -- that's got to be 1,200 liters.
你  你
Where-- Where--
你怎么知道如何把这些组合在一起的
How did you know how to put this all together?
有像你一样的高人相助
I had excellent help, as will you.
为这可筹划了好一阵子
Quite a lot of planning went into this.
我看也是
I would say so.
楼上的洗衣房
The laundry upstairs--
我经营多年了
I've owned it for years.
每周都会收到
It receives large
大量洗涤剂之类的东西
chemical deliveries on a weekly basis, detergent and such.
完全不惹人怀疑
There is nothing suspicious about it,
当然  我的手下
and my employees, to be sure,
都训练有素  值得信赖
are well-trained, trustworthy.
空气过滤系统是最新进的
The filtration system is state-of-the-art.
它只会排放出干净无味的蒸汽
It will vent nothing but clean, odorless steam,
就和普通洗衣房的蒸汽一样
just as the laundry does,
排烟管道也是一样的
and through the very same stacks.
我每周需要200磅[约92千克]
I need 200 pounds per week
这样才能维持这里的开销
to make this economically viable.
当然  只要你完成每周的任务
You would choose your own hours, of course,
你可以自己安排时间
come and go as you please
想来就来  想走便走
so long as the quota is met.
抱歉
Sorry.
我还是不同意
The answer is still no.
我已经做了一系列错误的决定
I have made a series of very bad decisions,
不能再继续错下去了
and I cannot make another one.
你为什么做了那些决定
Why did you make these decisions?
为了我的家庭
For the good of my family.
那么那些决定就没有错
Then they weren't bad decisions.
沃尔特  男人应该做什么
What does a man do, Walter?
男人要挣钱养家
A man provides for his family.
但这勾当让我失去了家庭
This cost me my family.
只要你的孩子在  家就在
When you have children, you always have family.
他们就是你最关心的  是你的责任
They will always be your priority, your responsibility,
作为男人  就要养家糊口
and a man-- a man provides.
就算他不被理解
And he does it
不受尊敬
even when he's not appreciated
甚至不再被爱着
or respected
他依然要这么做
or even loved.
他就这么担起一切  毫无怨言
He simply bears up, and he does it...
只因  他是男人
because he's a man.
要不要随便吃点
Any chance we could grab a quick bite?
街角的泰国菜馆很不错
Thai place around the corner's pretty good.
我真的得回家了
Um, I really gotta head home.
好吧  那改天吧
All right, rain check, then.
她说那是豆腐
She said it was the tofu.
不管怎么说  她真可爱
Whatever. She's still cute anyways.
晚饭很棒  妈妈
Uh, great-- great dinner, Mom.
是啊
Yeah.
我能离开一下吗
Um, can I be-- can I be excused?
做作业还是玩游戏
To do homework or to play videogames?
我能一心二用
I can multitask.
去吧
Go ahead.
你想抱抱她吗
You want to take her?
是啊
Yeah.
说点什么  安迪  快点
Give me something, Andy. Come on.
房车被焊进了一栋房子的后面  真经典
Welded onto the back of a house. Wow, that's classy.
天啊
Christ.
好的好的  谢谢
Okay. Okay, thanks.
喂  詹妮斯  詹妮斯
Hey, Janice. Janice.
最后一辆吗
That the last one?
抱歉  汉克  车管所注册的就这么多
Sorry, Hank. That's all DMV had--
一共29辆注册在新墨西哥州的80年代房车
29 early '80s Bounders registered in New Mexico.
你能再核对一遍吗
Could you check again?
现在么
Now?
派对完了我再弄行吗
Can I do it after the party?
詹妮斯  我...
Janice, I'm--
我彻底歇菜了
I'm dead in the water here.
好吧  我会再核对的
Okay, I'll check.
谢谢
Thanks.
格米  小鸟要出巢了
Gomie, time for the little bird to fly the nest, huh?
他们真是选对了人
They got the right guy for the job,
尤其是要和那些墨西哥人打交道
specially since the bean-speak comes natural and all.
想知道西班牙语里"去死吧"怎么说吗
Wanna know how to say "Get bent" In Spanish?
别怪我老土  行吗
Just don't go native on me, all right?
哦  对了
Oh, uh--
伙计
Hey, uh--
给你
Here.
知己知彼  百战不殆
Know your enemy and all.
好好打一仗  兄弟
Fight the good fight, brother.
我会的
I will.
有喝的吗
What have we got to drink around here?
你的直觉是对的
Your hunch was right.
还有一辆房车
One more RV.
车管所说注册没有续期
DMV said the registration wasn't renewed,
之后他们意识到  这辆车要么注册成非运营车辆
but then they realized it was never filed
要么就是被销毁了
as non-operational or destroyed.
也没有警方的报告
No police report, either.
我现在真的不知道
I just don't know
自己到底在干什么  明白么
what the hell I'm doing anymore, you know?
我好像被困住了
It's like I'm paralyzed,
不论我采取怎样的行动
like if I take a step in any direction,
都会犯下一个严重的错误
I'm going to make a spectacular mistake.
天啊  我真想借酒浇愁
God, I could go for a glass of wine about now.
你想去...
You want to go to--
算了  别在意
Sorry, never mind.
不管怎么说  有个事
Anyway, breaking news is
我现在和我的老板上床
I am sleeping with my boss,
但我不知道为什么
and I don't know why.
-哇  -是啊
- Wow. - Yep.
我撒谎了
That's a lie.
我知道为什么
I do know why.
他是个有魅力的男人
I mean, he's a lovely guy.
他是个很好的人
He's-- He's a really good person,
但是我们并不会....
but, I mean, it's not like we're ever gonna--
不知怎么的  我自己也不能相信
Somehow, and I can't actually believe it,
但我全家
but my entire family
都说我是...
sees me as some sort of--
我亲妹妹
my own sister,
我妹夫
my brother-in-law.
我那十多岁的儿子都说我是个婊子
My teenage son tells me I'm a bitch.
你让我告诉他真相
And you say tell him the truth.
告诉他  他爸爸是究竟是怎样的人
Tell him about his father,
我做不到
but I can't...ever.
我怎么能
How could I?
现在和我上床的这个人
And this man that I'm seeing,
尽管我知道这不对
you know, as wrong as I know it is,
但我仍然要这么做
as much as I know I'm probably doing it
我想让沃尔特离开我
just to make Walt leave me,
一天中  这是唯一不令我
it is the only thing in my day
感到自己正在...
where I don't feel...
正在...
like I'm...
沉沦的事情
drowning.
他知道你外面有男人的咯
So he knows about this other man?
知道
Yeah.
他会签离婚文件吗
So then he'll sign?
沃尔特说他哪也不会去
Um, Walt says he's not going anywhere,
所以
so that's a--
这招对付我太管用了
that's a really brilliant gambit on my part.
是啊
Yep.
聪明
Genius.
他把钱藏在家里
He keeps money in the house.
你丈夫  那个毒贩
Your husband, the drug dealer?
有多少钱
How much money?
我没数
I didn't count it.
钱很重
It's-- It's heavy.
都放在一个包里
The bag where he keeps it.
你是在求我让你花那笔钱吗
Are you asking my permission to spend this money?
不  天啊  不是
No. God, no.
不  我只是
I-- No, I'm just, you know--
我不过是想谈谈而已
I'm just trying to just talk it through. That's--
我得说明一点  在律师这做心理辅导
Let me just say that I'm half as qualified
可是双倍的价钱  一半的疗效
and twice the price of a therapist.
这没什么好讨论的  斯凯勒
There is nothing to discuss here, Skyler.
我只是陈述
I'm just saying, you know?
我们曾是夫妻
We have a history.
他还是孩子的父亲
He's the father of my children,
可能他的所作所为
and maybe what he did, he--
是为了这个家  对吧
He did it for the family. Right?
好吧  动动脑子
Well, guess what.
这完全是胡扯
That is one enormous load of horse shit.
好吧
Okay.
我得简单为你说明一下
I'm going to spell this out as simply as I can for you.
你要是在那屋子
You are a fool
再多呆一分钟
to stay in that house
你就是一个大笨蛋
one minute longer.
他不走就你走
If your husband won't leave, then you go.
你现在可犯了知情罪了
You are now an accessory after the fact.
会被判刑
You are culpable.
你  还有孩子
You, your children,
你们会一无所有
you could lose everything you own.
懂吗
Do you understand?
你不离婚
All courtesy of this criminal
就是在包容罪犯
you refuse to divorce.
我并没有嫁给一个罪犯
I didn't marry a criminal.
但现在是了
Well, you're married to one now.
我们再练习一遍
Hows about we run through this thing one more time,
特别是该由我说话的地方
especially the part where I do all the talking
你别插嘴
and you don't say jack?
我就要插嘴
Oh, I'm going to say jack.
还要大说特说
I'm going to say plenty.
我们这是在互相较劲吗
What did we say about escalating, huh?
过去是谁为你擦屁股的
Who's got your back here, hm?
是我  好了  这事我来搞定
Me. All right? I'm going to take care of things.
可你打算怎么让自己
Hey, what are the parameters
能够一直保持清醒呢
of this sobriety thing you got going?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你能吃安宁神吗
Can you take a Xanax?
我这儿有一抽屉
'Cause I got a drawer full of them.
"脊椎神经医师"给我配的
I get them from my "Chiropractor."
越南人  1米52
Vietnamese, 5 foot tall,
她能让你安眠到天亮
she adjusts you to completion.
她叫金玉霜
Her name's Kim Nu Suong,
人如其名
as delicious as it sounds.
我该把她的名片给你
I should give you her card.
让这些玩意见鬼去吧
To hell with this.
让他进来
Send him in.
你好  沃尔特
Hello, Walt.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
请坐这边
Please, have a seat... here.
平克曼先生  你也请坐
Mr. Pinkman, if you will.
你来晚了
You're late.
先生们  如果我们都已达成共识
Gentlemen, if we could come to some accommodation here now.
那么一切都将迎刃而解
There's always a way to oil everyone's lock.
这位年轻小伙
This young man
很善心地打算为你
is prepared to offer you
提供分红
a sweetheart of a deal doing precisely nothing.
是吗
Really?
他以后独自制毒所得
10 percent of all future profits
收益的10%归你
from his solo venture
你只需直接去信箱拿这笔钱就好
is money you get paid for walking down to the mailbox.
只管把它当成
Consider it a gesture of respect
对于你目前所做的贡献
for your valuable contributions
而表示的一份心意吧
to the business thus far.
我肯定你会欣然接受
I'm sure you'll agree that's fair.
就是笔施舍费
That's charity, is what that is.
所有事都由我搞定
I do all the work.
他则无所事事  说长道短
He sits around on his fat a-- judging people.
喂  喂  别火上浇油
Hey, hey, hey. Escalating.
够了
Stop.
大致就是这样
So here's that,
但出了点小问题
but then there's one small detail.
显然我们的联络人
Clearly a mistake was made
出了点状况
on the part of our mutual associate
他把杰西挣的另一半钱给了你
when he paid you half of Jesse's earnings.
他显然还不知道
He must not have realized that you two
你们俩已经分道扬镳了
had come to a parting of the ways.
拿去  归你了
Take it. It belongs to you.
你他妈太对了  本来就是我的
You're damn right it belongs to me.
我就知道你们俩客气着呢
I knew I could count on you boys to play nice.
快把我感动地泪流满面了
That's-- That almost brings a tear to my eye.
尽情享用吧  趁着年轻
Enjoy it. Spend it in good health.
这是你在这行的最后一桶金了
That is the last money you'll ever earn in this business.
你他妈什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
好吧  我本不想讲清楚  杰西
Well, I hate to break it to you, Jesse,
但我们的联络人
but our mutual associate
只是利用你  找到我而已
was only using you to get to me.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
正如你所见  他更需要有此专长的人
You see, he needs someone with expertise,
一个清楚他意图的人
someone who knows what he's doing.
换句话说  他需要的是我
In other words, he needs me.
你是想说  你又开始制毒了吗
You're telling me you're cooking again?
正是
Yeah, uh--
该怎么向你解释呢
How should I put this?
我入伙了  你出局了
I'm in. You're out.
沃尔特  等一下
Whoa, whoa, Walt, hold on there.
冒昧地问一句
Uh, what was the offer,
报酬是多少
if I may ask?
三个月  三百万
It's, uh, 3 million for three months of my time.
你需要把这些钱洗白吧
What You're gonna need that money laundered, right?
理所当然
I mean, of course.
我们之前怎么说的
What was our deal before?
17%  有点虚高
17 percent. That's a shade high.
那就15%吧
Let's settle on an even 15.
这个数不错
That's a nice round number.
5%
5 percent.
-14%也很公平  -5%
- 14's fair. - 5.
-13%  -5%
- 13. - 5.
12%  看在以往情面上  12%
12. For old time's sake, 12.
5%
5.
我是个通情达理的人  而且是短期合作
I'm a reasonable guy. It's a short-term deal.
那就10%吧
10 even,
不能再低了  给我点面子
but I can't go any lower and still respect myself.
-就5%吧  -这是怎么一回事
- 5. - What in the hell just happened?
你是我的律师  不是他的
You're my lawyer, not his!
这就是现实  孩子
That's the way of the world, kid.
弱肉强食
You go with the winner.
你以为这样就能让我罢手吗
You think this'll stop me from cooking?
悉听尊便
Cook whatever you like...
继续加你的辣椒面或是其他垃圾
As long as it's that ridiculous "Chili P" Or some other drek,
但别妄想用我的配方
but don't even think about using my formula.
尽管放马过来吧  贱人
Just try and stop me, bitch.
有事吗
Yes?
是奥尔特加夫人吗
Hi, there, uh, Mrs. Ortega?
是我
Yes.
你好  我是汉克·施拉德
Hi, I'm Hank Schrader.
毒品缉私局警员
I'm with the Drug Enforcement Administration.
我们正在调查一辆休闲车
We're interested in an RV
是用你的名字和地址注册
that's registered to your name and address.
你买过休闲车吗
Uh, do you have an RV?
我买过
I did.
但几个月前被偷了
It was stolen months ago.
被偷了
Stolen, huh?
对此我很好奇
Well, then I'm curious as to
为何失窃没有上报呢
why the theft was never reported.
在警局或是车管所并没有相关记录
I'm not seeing any records of it with the police or the DMV.
我没有时间
I just... didn't get around to it.
我能问问原因吗
May I ask why?
有了车  就能和家人
I mean it's a-- it's a great way to get the family together
一起平价出游
for an affordable vacation.
所以车子丢了  你一定很心痛
It must've been quite a blow when it went missing.
确实如此
It was.
你觉得
Do you have any ideas at all
会是谁偷了车子呢
who might've taken it?
我不想看他被捕
I didn't want him arrested.
他虽终日与坏人厮混
He ran with a bad crowd,
但本质不坏
but he was never a bad person.
我相信他会重新做人
I thought he could turn his life around.
你说的是谁  奥尔特加夫人
Who are we talking about, Mrs. Ortega?
我儿子
My son.
我真的很想和他谈谈
I'd really like to speak with him.
他去世了
He's passed away.
两个月前被人枪杀
He was shot two months ago.
你儿子叫什么名字
What was your son's name?
克里斯蒂安
Christian.
克里斯蒂安·奥尔特加
Christian Ortega.
他的绰号是康宝吗
Was his nickname "Combo"?
谢谢你的配合  感激之至
Thanks for this. I really appreciate it.